Joana Castaneda

Portfolio: https://joanacastaneda.github.io/Portfolio/ Languages: English (Advanced), French (Intermediate) and Spanish (Mother tongue)



343 585-5290

dg.joana24@gmail.com

GRAPHIC COMMUNICATION DESIGN

As a candidate, I have gained four years of experience designing for government institutions, private companies, and nonprofit organizations through various volunteer projects. I typically collaborated with the IT department as a web and graphic designer. Over these years, I have created a range of digital content, including websites, social media posts, videos, animations, banners, landing pages, logos, infographics, icons, and print materials.

Education

Attestation de formation de connaissance de la langue française Cégep de Rosemont, Montréal, QC, CA. Nov. 2023 - Nov. 2024

Diploma, Game Programming 2021 - 2023 St. Lawrence College, Cornwall, ON, CA.

Degree, Graphic Communication Design 2012 - 2016 Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, México City.

Technical Skills

- Graphic design / Animation and Modeling / Digital and printed design
- Web design: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Game design: C++, Unity, Phaser
- Experienced with libraries like jQuery UI, jQuery Mobile, Bootstrap
- Use of WordPress, Wix, Figma and Canva
- Design software like Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere, After Effects, Audition, Lightroom, Dreamweaver, InDesign, and Blender
- Office library: Word, PowerPoint, and Excel
- Knowledge of PhoneGap, Jira and GitHub
- Knowledge of SEO practices

Work Experience

Graphic Designer

December 2024 – Present

Empowered Futures / (Non-profit organization)

• Design and contribute to various tasks within the marketing department to develop strategies that enhance the organization's presence.

Graphic / Web Designer

October 2023 - January 2024

ACOMM / (Freelance project to renovate a website for an organization in Montreal)

• Design a prototype in Figma for the latest version of some sections of the website ACOMM taking into consideration the values of the organization.

Graphic Designer Volunteer

July 2023 – October 2023

BTSADV / (Volunteer for a nonprofit organization who helps women in USA)

- Elaborate flyers and invitations for events, promotions, and awareness of BTSADV.
- Create designs, concepts, and posts for social media.

Web and Graphic Designer

2017 - 2021

Tax Administration Service / (government institution in Mexico)

- Updated the website's applications with new sections and content.
- Designed new applications which answer to the needs of each department.
- Optimized the main portal website making it easier for the employees to find the information to complete their activities on time.
- Created digital content for the needs of the institution like videos, tutorials, banners, landing pages, infographics, icons, presentations, and posts for social media.
- Dealt with the lack of communication between different areas creating alerts in the systems and sending a news section through the email.
- Stimulated the working environment with the suggestion of designing videos to show appreciation for the accomplished goals of the employees.

Web designer

July 2017 - October 2017

We R Unlimited / (Web Agency in Mexico City)

- Contributed to the development of a website for the Genuino Metco company designing a clean and friendly interface (https://www.metco.com.mx/).
- Design of 6 mini-sites: AzucarBC, Svetia, Mascabado, DBsugar, Piloncillo and Sweet-0.

Graphic designer

2016 - 2017

Goros Lotu / (*Transport Company in Mexico City*)

- Established an image more coherent and clearer designing digital and printed material.
- Optimized prices in printing materials and negotiating with the suppliers the best options.

Soft Skills

- Effective communication, I try my best to listen and be clear to avoid misunderstandings in any task.
- Positive attitude, I perform my activities with kindness and respect.
- **Time management**, I have experience of knowing what to prioritize and organize.
- Responsible, I do the tasks assigned with professionalism and with the values of the company.
- **Creative**, I like to think of options and ideas to improve the service.
- **Team worker**, I enjoy working in a team.